Don't improvise, Barbara.
Dance the dance
as you learned it.
Admit it, Scott. We're
very good together.
Barbara. Please.
So this is the secret
to your success.
It's not enough to teach
them how to dance.
You have to throw in a
little cheap romance too.
Laura, it's not what you think.
I know what I saw.
Laura!
Laura.
Forget it, Scott.
Laura, I love you.
My attorney will begin
dissolving this partnership
in the morning.
Are you out of your mind?
All the woman did was kiss me.
What about the
others? What others?
You know exactly
what I'm talking about.
No, I don't.
I'm the one who
wants to get married.
You're the one who
won't leave your husband.
My husband's money
set you up in this business,
and now I'm gonna
close you down.
Laura.
Tough luck, old buddy.
Getting caught like that.
Somebody told her I
was playing around.
You wouldn't have any
idea who that could be?
None.
None at all.
Who do you suppose knew
I would be helping
Barbara tonight,
and called Laura and
told her to come down?
Beats me.
But if you have to look to
see who's watching you,
you shouldn't be
doing it in the first place.
Good night.
Out late again, my dear.
Oh, Garland. You startled me.
Committee meeting.
Yes, dear.
The opera ball. You remember?
I thought the committee
had finished its work.
Well, they're tying things up.
Please don't be
tedious, darling.
I am absolutely dead.
Good night.
Laura, give it a chance.
This is all a big mistake.
I've worked too hard to
let you pull the plug now.
Laura.
Laura?
Do you have any
idea why your wife
was, uh, headed
out that way tonight?
No. Uh...
Uh, perhaps a charity
board meeting, or...
Yeah.
Well, maybe she got
her dates mixed up.
Bob, I think you
better come outside
and take a look at something.
Recognize this fabric?
Yes. It's part of the dress
my wife was wearing today.
Oh, my God. How
did this get there?
Where were you
tonight, Mr. Frazier?
At home.
All evening?
Yes, yes.
Can anyone verify that?
Oh, yes. My houseman, Chester.
Bob, I found this.
This, uh, pen belong to you?
I've never seen it before.
They all look alike,
so I cut a notch in
the screw cap, there.
Then, uh... this is your pen.
Where'd you find it?
Found it on the floor of the car
that killed Laura Frazier.
How did it get there?
Well, now, that's another
good question, Scott.
What's this?
I don't know.
Well, looks like they match.
This is the key to
Garland Frazier's car.
The one that was used
to run down his wife.
And this is a duplicate.
Scott, I'm afraid I'm
going to have to ask you
to come downtown.
Yes, Laura and I
were having an affair.
Yes, she put up the
money for the dance studio.
Yes, we had a little
argument, personal.
I don't care what
Dash Hamilton said.
I didn't kill Laura,
Mr. Matlock.
I loved her.
You making any money?
Studio is successful.
How long have you been
taking dance lessons?
About a year, year and a half.
Oh, off and on.
About that.
Can you dance?
He's all right.
Huh.
Well, give me a
couple of minutes.
I'll see if I can take the case.
Well, thanks, Ben.
And, uh, listen, I'm
sorry about, uh...
Yeah.
It's okay.
Well.
So...
She got the place
if you died first.
Yes.
And you got it
if she went first.
Yes.
Where were you last night?
Home.
Alone?
Yes. Figures.
I didn't do it.
Someone planted that evidence.
Well...
I'll tell you what a
jury's gonna see.
Jury's gonna see
this younger man
romancing this older woman,
taking her money from her.
And she gets the feeling
she's being two-timed,
and he kills her.
I'm just telling you
what a jury's gonna think.
They're gonna
think you're a gigolo.
Well, it's not true!
I loved Laura.
I don't care what
you or anyone thinks.
Look, I'll understand if
you don't want to take the case.
Maybe you could just...
recommend someone.
Ow!
Ah! Oh.
Oh. Oh, Ben.
I thought you were an intruder.
Oh, no, I just
fell over that chair
that used to be
in the living room.
Oh, I'm so sorry
about the chair,
but I thought it was
lost in the living room.
Well, I found it in the hall.
What are you doing home?
Oh, I was gonna
call, but it was so late.
What happened
to your fishing trip?
Ah, this case came up.
Oh, that's too bad.
Are you sure you're all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Where did I hit you?
Right here. Right...
Oh! Can I fix you something?
No, I'm fine.
I think I'll just go to bed.
Oh.
What's the matter?
I'm in your bed.
Oh. Um...
Ben, I don't think it's a
good idea for me to stay here.
Why not?
Well... Well, you can't go home.
The workmen will be at
your house for two weeks.
Yes, I know. But today I saw
your neighbors looking over.
And they must think...
Well, the hell with them.
Oh, we have rights. Well...
Oh, I don't think so.
Ugh. I'll tell you what.
Why don't you just
go on back to bed?
I'll sleep across the hall.
No, no, no. Let me... No, no,
no, no, no. no. I'm
really wiped out.
I'll just go on back and I'll...
I'll see you in the morning.
You all right?
I just knocked over
my alarm clock.
Yeah, I heard the noise.
I was afraid you would.
Well, I figured it was a
clock or a glass or something.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to wake you.
That's okay.
Are... Are you
sure you're all right?
Oh, yes.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Well, good morning.
Good morning. How did you sleep?
Fine. How about you?
Fine. Good.
Of course, I woke you once.
Oh, just once. Heh.
How's your...?
Oh, fine. See.
Mmm. Bacon and eggs.
Yes. I've kept a
plate hot for you.
Ah. I can't eat bacon and eggs.
Cholesterol.
Oh, I'm sorry. What can you eat?
This stuff here.
The doctor told me I had
to cut back on cholesterol.
I'll get the milk.
Skim.
Uh, have you seen the "Metro"?
Oh, yes. Here it is.
Oh.
Here's the rest of it.
Oh. Have you finished?
Yeah. All right.
I hope you're not
one of those people
who hates sharing the newspaper.
No. I like sharing the
newspaper. Heh-heh.
'Course, uh, here at
home, I don't usually.
I know. You're alone.
Yeah.
Hm.
Ben, excuse me, but
we have a problem.
We do?
Uh-huh. The Scott Lazar case.
Oh, you've been assigned.
Yes, I just got the call.
Oh.
Well, I think that's fine.
We have a very strong case.
I'm sure you do.
Word is he's a gigolo.
Yeah. I... I hear
he likes women.
How did you get involved?
Well... You're not
gonna believe it.
Bob Brooks studied
dancing under Scott Lazar.
Lieutenant Brooks?
Yeah, I guess his wife
made him. I don't know.
Oh! Oh, so... So you're
doing it as a favor.
Yeah, I'll give it
my best shot. Oh.
Do you think I should move out?
Of here? Yes.
No.
You don't think it will
affect our relationship?
Well, why should it?
We've argued cases before.
Yes, I know.
Well, there you go.
Miss March.
Thank you.
Um, Your Honor,
Scott Lazar has been a resident
of the state of Georgia
for less than two years.
He has no real ties
to this community,
and the state feels that
risk of flight is substantial.
Therefore, we ask
that bail be denied.
Your Honor, if the
courts denied bail
to everyone in Atlanta who's
lived here less than two years,
then it would deny freedom
to half the
citizens of the city.
Uh, and excuse me for saying,
that would include
our learned prosecutor,
who has lived here
under two years herself.
That is a specious
argument, Your Honor.
May I remind the eminent
counsel for the defense
that we're not talking about
an ordinary citizen here.
We're talking about a young man
who has been
living off the money
of an older, married woman
while he was seducing her.
Wait a minute, Your Honor.
We're not arguing the case here.
We're just discussing bail.
Your Honor, I am merely
stating matters of fact.
If... If I could just...
If I could just...
Counselors!
Are you lecturing me?
No.
Counselors! Will counsel
approach the bench?
Off the record.
I will not have this shouting
match in my courtroom.
Your Honor, we're just
having a reasoned argument.
Mr. Matlock, that'll be enough.
Back on the record. As
far as bail is concerned,
prosecution's
argument is well taken.
Bail is denied.
Thank you, Your
Honor. But Your Honor...
Mr. Matlock, that is all.
I'm sorry, but I do
think that was fair.
Oh, I suppose.
Are you coming
home for dinner? Yeah.
Good.
I'll make you the best fried
chicken you've ever had.
Yeah? Yeah.
You know, it must
be terribly painful
for you to hear some
of the things being said
about your marriage.
Mm, yes, but of
course, I know the truth.
Laura and I were
very happy together.
What is that?
Oh, uh, that, uh, is a
trophy for the mambo.
Laura and, uh, her
partner earned that
in Montreal... last summer.
It's just... Ugly, isn't it?
Well, she was a champion
ballroom dancer, wasn't she?
Yes, yes. I...
must confess I never
understood her interest
in ballroom dancing.
But far be it for me
to squelch her passion.
Mr. Frazier, I'm...
embarrassed to ask,
but you did know
about your wife's affair
with Scott Lazar?
No, not at all.
And I must say I'm shocked
to hear such unfounded
and vicious gossip.
Oh.
Didn't you hire a
private investigator
to spy on your wife?
Who said anything of the sort?
But you did hire the
Temple Detective Agency.
Well, suppose I did.
There's no great crime in that.
And... to be painfully honest...
I had heard rumors
about Laura and her...
gigolo friend.
Was your wife aware that
you knew about her affair?
Well, I never found
any actual evidence,
so naturally I didn't
discuss it with her.
One of my Washington friends
heard about your
being considered
for an ambassadorial post.
Nothing has come of it yet.
You could stand to lose a lot
if there was some
sort of scandal.
You could make a case for that.
A suspicious person
might consider that a motive
for murder, Mr. Frazier.
I'm sure he could.
But I didn't commit murder...
and no one can prove that I did.
So you're wasting
your time... and mine.
And I could make an
even stronger case for that.
Hello?
That's pretty fancy footwork.
Why, thank you.
Don't you just
love the merengue?
It's very impressive.
Uh... could you tell me
where I might find, uh,
Mrs. Barbara Raymond?
I might.
Who are you?
Ben Matlock. Uh,
Scott Lazar's lawyer.
I'm Barbara.
Oh.
Uh... may I ask you
some questions?
Well, I hope you don't
mind if I continue to practice.
My partner is late, and
we only have two weeks
until the competition.
Uh... that... That competition.
Is that the same one that
you were rehearsing for
with Scott Lazar when
he had his argument
with, uh, Laura Frazier?
Yes, but that was a tango.
This is a merengue.
Well, how involved were
you with Scott Lazar?
Well, since you
are his attorney,
I expect you to keep
this in confidence.
Okay.
Scott and I are lovers.
According to Scott, you were...
attached to him, but...
there was nothing to it.
Well, yes. That's,
uh, Scott's way.
And I agree, Mr. Matlock.
Discretion would be best
under the circumstances.
Well...
I think the truth would
be the most helpful.
Well, let's just say that
Scott and I were good friends,
and Laura misapprehended
the situation.
You told the police that
at the time of the murder,
you were at a tanning salon.
I would appreciate it if you
kept that in confidence too.
Though I do go
there once a week.
Well, um, uh... M-Mrs.
Raymond... uh...
Ben. Spending some
of your exorbitant fees
on dance lessons?
Oh, Archibald.
You're the last person
I'd have expected to see here.
Judge Smith is
my dancing partner.
Well, actually, I-I'm just
here working on a case.
Well, actually, I'm just here
working on the merengue.
Well... you were
right about one thing.
This is the best fried
chicken I ever had.
You're just being kind.
No, no, no. I'm not.
It's the best.
I was just kidding when I
said it would be the best.
Are you sure that's okay?
It's the best.
With all the fried chicken
you've ever had in your life?
Julie... I don't say
this to just anyone
that rolls some
chicken in batter,
throws it in a
skillet and fries it up.
Your chicken is the best.
It's got the crispiest
skin, the juiciest meat,
the most perfect
flavor I ever tasted.
It's the best.
Oh.
Let me put it this way.
My mother... my very own mother
who won blue
ribbons at state fairs,
never made fried
chicken as good as yours.
Hah! Ben, I don't
know what to say.
It's the best.
Would you like some more?
No.
My doctor would fire me
if he knew I ate this much.
Oh, I forgot. Your cholesterol.
I'm sorry.
Oh, that's okay. I'll eat
cardboard tomorrow.
But it was really good.
It was the best.
Well, ahem, I, um...
I had a couple of
interesting developments
in the Scott Lazar case.
Ben, I don't think we
should discuss that.
It's not unethical.
You know what I mean.
To you, Scott Lazar
is the victim of a frame.
To me, he's a murdering gigolo.
Oh, well. I wouldn't
call him a gigolo.
I mean, I know
you don't like him,
and you think he's guilty,
but to call him a gigolo
is kind of like street talk.
Oh, come on, Ben.
He is what he is:
a good-looking guy
who trades on his charm.
Well, Scott's a professional.
He... He... He offers a service.
A service for older women.
Well... Yes. And a lot of them.
The fact that he was in
love with Laura Frazier
has nothing to do with that.
The fact that he used
her for her money does.
They were legal partners.
They were until he killed her.
Well, I don't
think he killed her.
What happened to the
presumption of innocence anyway?
Want some coffee? No, thank you.
Ben, I refuse to argue
this case out of court.
Well, who's arguing?
And I also refuse
to be put on trial
for my personal point of view.
We're just having a
discussion, for Pete's sake.
Oh, excuse me.
Where you going? I'm
going to take a shower.
You just had one.
I'm going to take another one.
I happen to like showers.
Damn.
Good morning. Good morning.
So how'd you sleep?
Just beautifully. And you?
Okay.
Just okay?
Maybe that fried
chicken set heavy.
Now, here is your
cereal, your milk,
your pills, your paper,
including the ever-popular
"Metro" section.
Now, I don't know
whether you take sugar
in your cereal or not,
but here it is just in case.
I have a breakfast meeting,
so I'll be running along now.
Have a wonderful breakfast.
See you in court. Bye.
I'm really looking forward
to working with you, Letitia.
Oh, well, I always
wanted to learn the tango.
My guess is,
is that you're
championship material.
Oh!
We'd find out sooner
if you doubled up
on your lessons.
But I just bought
a year's worth.
Two years costs...
just a few dollars
more than one.
Ooh!
I hadn't thought
of it quite that way.
Ciao.
Now that is some
sales pitch, Mr. Harrison.
Have we met?
Tyler Hudson.
I'm working on the Scott
Lazar case with Ben Matlock.
Not interested.
Now this could take
a couple seconds
of your valuable time, sir.
Or we can drag you into court.
I hadn't thought
of it quite that way.
So you attended a
local softball game
the night Laura
Frazier was murdered.
That's right.
I don't suppose
anyone saw you there
who could
corroborate your story.
I'm new in the neighborhood.
I don't know anyone.
Look, I already told
the police everything.
No. Not everything.
According to Scott,
you were Laura's lover
before he came into the picture.
So what?
So we heard that she intended
to set you up in
your own studio.
But those plans changed
when she met Scott.
My friend, you're
whistling in the wind.
Ah, but a man in
your dancing shoes
must have found
it pretty difficult
taking orders from
her new boyfriend.
Look, chum...
Scott killed Laura.
We'll see, chum.
We'll see.
Mr. Frazier, are you connected
with the Frazier
Building downtown?
Yes. My father
built it 50 years ago.
I believe it was
sold three years ago.
A distress sale, wasn't it?
Yes. I had some minor
cash flow problems.
An oil lease in the Middle East
was, uh, affected
by the... trouble there.
Well, that must be nice,
to have a... A building to sell
when you need to
raise a little cash.
Most people have to
settle for a swap meet.
Your Honor.
Mr. Matlock, I assume
this is leading somewhere.
Your Honor, I assure you it is.
Proceed.
Uh, have you ever heard
of the Christian
Ferrare Jewelers?
Oh, yes. I-I've, uh,
purchased some items,
uh, from them in the past.
Ever sold anything?
I-I can't recall.
Well, maybe this will
refresh your memory.
Uh, a diamond and
emerald necklace,
several other items, uh...
three months ago.
Oh. Yes.
Uh, these belonged to,
uh, Mrs. Frazier, didn't they?
Yes.
Did she know you sold them?
Uh... I-I don't think so.
N-not at the time.
So you have testified...
that to raise cash,
you sold a building,
some jewels...
Yes, but what does that
have to do with Laura's death?
Maybe you'd better let
me ask the questions.
Um... last year, you took out
an insurance policy on your wife
in the amount of $2 million.
Isn't that true?
Yes. But, uh, taking out
insurance i-i-is not unusual.
No. No, no, it's not,
but as you say, with
the soft oil market,
and your having to,
uh, sell off assets,
it appears that
maybe you were living
in a financial house of cards
that could've come crumbling
around you at any minute.
Mr. Matlock, I did
not kill my wife!
I was home.
My houseman has
already testified to that.
Uh, your houseman,
Chester Grant,
was nowhere near
your estate that night.
He was playing poker.
Ordinarily, he plays
poker on Thursdays,
but it was postponed because
one of the regulars was ill.
Now, that player is prepared
to testify to that,
if necessary.
Where were you, Mr. Frazier?
You were not at home.
Why did you lie?
To protect someone.
Who?
Someone I love very
much. My... M-my daughter.
You and Mrs.
Frazier... had a child?
Laura was not the mother.
Well, who's the mother?
Her name was Caroline Blum.
She worked in an art gallery.
I... I barely knew her.
I had a casual affair years ago.
Caroline became pregnant and...
elected to have the child
over... my objections.
Oh, I told Laura
about it... hm...
and... And Laura stayed with me,
but, well, it ruined
the marriage.
I tried to keep it very quiet.
I... supported the
mother, the child.
And then last
year, Caroline died.
Oh, um... where has, uh...
your daughter lived
since her mother died?
I-I found a place for her
with the... The sister
of my houseman.
See, I was with my daughter
the night Laura was murdered.
I...
No, I didn't take the Mercedes,
because i-i-it was
so conspicuous.
And I got home just
before the police arrived.
No further questions.
Cross-examine?
No questions, Your Honor.
Court stands adjourned
till 9 a.m. tomorrow morning.
What do we do now?
Well, I... I guess
we'd better regroup.
Believe me, it's
all in her mind.
Did you see Julie leave?
No.
You ever been to
a tanning salon?
Hey, Julie.
Hey, Julie, I'm home.
I brought Chinese.
Got all your favorites.
Hey, Julie, where are you?
Dear Ben, you've been so kind
to let me stay here,
but I think things
would be simpler if I go.
Thank you for everything.
Julie.
"P.S. Leftover chicken
warming in the oven.
I hope it will be okay."
Julie?
Hi.
Hi. Thanks for the
chicken. It was good.
Sometimes it's better left over.
Even cold.
It was.
Did I forget to
turn on the oven?
Oh, no. Um...
I'm... I'm sorry
you left like that.
Ben... So... So we...
We argue a little.
Who doesn't?
I know. But neither
one of us likes to give in.
Heh. I know.
Um...
besides wanting to tell
you I'm sorry you left,
I have to tell you
I think I'm onto something...
that'll clear Scott Lazar.
Excuse me.
Yes.
He's right here. It's Michelle.
Yeah, Michelle?
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Okay. Uh... Uh, gimme...
Gimme 20 minutes.
I've got to go.
I really think we're
onto something,
and I just wanted
you to know, and...
I hope you know...
how fond I am of you,
how much I enjoy your company,
and you... You really do
make great fried chicken.
And I'm sorry about
our disagreement.
If you wanna call Scott
Lazar a gigolo, that's fine.
I... I think he may
be a gigolo myself.
Anyway, I, uh... I just,
uh, wanted you to know
I really think we
are onto something,
and I'll see you later.
Well, what's the verdict?
Fifty seven, thirty four.
It's possible to make
the trip in an hour.
But not without speeding.
And I forgot about that
speed trap on Route 10.
Oh.
Can you fix a ticket?
No.
You know somebody?
I might.
Mrs. Raymond...
uh, you've been a
widow for seven years.
Is that right?
Yes.
And how have you filled the void
since your husband's death?
Uh, church, charity work?
No. Dancing.
Dancing.
That's right. You're, uh...
You're something of a
champion, aren't you?
Yes.
I have a silver
medal in the tango,
and I'm going for the gold.
Oh. Hm.
Uh... do you, uh, study dancing?
Yes.
For... For how long?
Five years.
Oh, that's right.
That's right. The
first four years
at the Holiday Dance Salon,
and then the last year
with, uh, Scott Lazar.
Yes.
I understand those, um...
Those, uh, dance
lessons are, um, expensive.
Uh... how did you afford them?
Well, mostly with my
husband's pension,
but I took out a
loan for the rest.
Mrs. Raymond...
you couldn't really afford...
those lessons.
They came...
at great sacrifice, didn't they?
And I... I guess, I... I
guess you wanted...
your money's worth,
and you allowed yourself
to slip into some
kind of fantasy.
A fantasy in which, uh,
Scott Lazar was...
Was your instructor,
but he was also
your... Your hero.
Your... knight in shining armor,
so to speak.
Could rescue you from...
the terror and loneliness
you felt as a widow.
Ah...
Uh, Mrs. Raymond...
isn't it true that
you were the one...
who called Laura Frazier
to come out to that
deserted road that night?
No.
And didn't you somehow manage
to borrow the keys
to the Frazier car
from Mrs. Frazier's purse
and have two copies made,
and place one copy...
in Scott Lazar's desk?
While you were doing that...
took out one of
his fountain pens
and planted it... in
the Frazier Mercedes.
No. This is all lies.
Scott and I are lovers.
We were wonderful together.
Yes, and that's right. You...
You were at your tanning salon
at the time of the murder.
You were supposed
to keep that confidential.
Everything has to come out now.
And I'll tell you what I think.
I think you killed
Laura Frazier...
and made it look like...
you were at your tanning
salon at the same time.
Why are you doing this to me?
You went to your tanning salon,
and yes, you signed in.
But you slipped out the
back door, didn't you?
I don't remember.
I think you did.
I think you slipped
out the back door...
went to the Frazier estate...
took the Frazier car...
drove out to that lonely road.
You knew Laura
Frazier would be there.
And then you used that car
to take her life away.
After the murder...
you drove back to
the Frazier estate...
and then you got in your own car
and drove like the wind
back to the tanning salon.
Went in the back door,
and made it appear
as if you had just
finished your session.
Oh, that is ridiculous.
No one can do all
of that in an hour.
That's right.
You'd really have to race.
And there's a speed
trap on Highway 10.
You were almost
certain to get a ticket.
I have never gotten a
speeding ticket in my life.
Are you sure a
motorcycle officer
didn't give you a
citation that night?
Yes.
You can just go to city
hall and check the records.
I did.
And you're right.
There is no citation.
Well, then... what
more do you want?
So we checked...
with all the officers
on duty that night.
When a citation is given,
there is the original.
That is sent to the
Department of Public Safety
to be processed in the courts.
And two duplicates.
The first duplicate
goes to the offender,
the second... to the officer.
Now, that original
is the one that
causes all the trouble...
unless you've got
someone who can fix it.
Do you have a friend
who can fix a ticket?
I don't know what you mean.
The Honorable Archibald Smith.
Your dance partner.
He can fix a ticket, can't he?
This is Officer
Kevin Miller's copy
of the citation he issued to you
the night Laura
Frazier was murdered.
It states that the
time was 8:33 p.m.,
and the vehicle you were
driving was Mrs. Frazier's.
Do you know what I
mean now, Mrs. Raymond?
We all know what it
means to be lonely.
I know I do.
It must've been very painful...
to love Scott Lazar...
and not have that love returned.
It still is.
Oh, Scott, I... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
Your Honor, under
the circumstances,
the state moves that the
charges against Scott Lazar
be dismissed.
By the people's motion,
this case is dismissed.
Court is adjourned.
Congratulations.
You do like
champagne, don't you?
Well, yeah.
You're right.
About what?
Good friends should
be able to argue.
Sometimes. But not tonight.
Here's to us.
Yeah.
You put on a fine case today.
Yes, but like you said, you...
knew something.
Oh. Heh.
Mmm. By the way,
the repairs on my house
are going to take
another two weeks.
Oh.
www.tvsubtitles.net